Hello, everyone, and
welcome to CS 6300 Office
Hour. This is the first
Office Hour of the semester.
My name is Xinxuan,
and I'm a head TA,
and with me is Professor
Paola Spolettini.
Paola.
Hey, hi, everybody. Welcome
to this spring semester 2026
and the first Office Hour.
and with us we also have
will johnson um he's
supposed to be a
presenter let me make a
quick change and now
will i think you can also
unmute yourself okay
hopefully uh yep nice
there we go hi everyone
uh nice to meet you
oh right so um we um i believe
all of the tas we already
introduced ourselves on
it and paula's bio is also
available on canvas so this
is the first office hour
usually we don't have very
much but let's go through
it regardless so let me
will do you have that uh at
I have it open. Yeah.
Please help me to go
through the question
first. I need to make
some housekeeping.
What, you want me to read the
questions and you
answer them? Yes.
Yeah, read the question first.
Okay. The first question
is, is the office
hour session related
to participation grade?
People have answered it.
Justin has put an answer,
so that's probably.
Yeah, so the only one
that's unresolved is,
will the Canvas calendar
be updated each week
with the most current
office hour time? This
week still shows the
meeting on the 22nd.
Yeah. I believe it
should be showing the
correct date and time.
That's it, the date and
time of your Canvas
local time configuration.
If that's not the
case, please inform us.
Yeah. And that is all the
questions we have
at the moment.
Okay, if that's
the case, any wise
words from instructor,
Paola or Will?
Oh, and I see one person
raising a hand. I believe
it is mentioned in the
ad post that if you have
any questions, please do
so in the ad post only.
You know, the problem is
because of their FERPA issues
with having students have
to be heard and seen on
the video. So it's just
easier to have people put
the questions over there
and answer them that way. So
we will watch for your
question over there.
Yeah, you can put it
now and we are going
to wait for them live,
but through the post.
Any wise words? Let's see.
so my suggestion is that
try to be on top of your
assignments and on top of
your um you know um on top of
your deadlines especially
in the group project just
coordinate well and not just
because uh you know like your
there is a peer review
process that counts for your
grade but also because it's
gonna improve your product
is part of the process so
as uh it's it's a it's all
right so if you if you wait
until the end it's uh it's
gonna show so just try to
be on top of your deadline
and um and i'm pretty sure
that will help you to do great
is it wise enough i don't
know will do you want to
add something wiser uh you
are much more experienced
than me in this class because
you've been doing it much
longer that's true but uh
shin will warn you that when
you say wise around me it
tends to mean wise *** so
but we do have another
question so uh we'll go to that
when should we expect
to receive our group
assignments and when do grade
releases normally happen
right so uh group
assignment we do have um on
the assignment release
date due date and late
due date already published
on canvas but i also
assume that the other
way to read this question
is when students know their
teammates in the group
project and to answer
that question um we the
instructional staff usually
release the team member
list close to the opening
of the group project the
group project opens on
saturday so usually well
actually uh step take a step
back the group project d0
which is only um contact
information opens on
saturday so uh the team
members will have um will know
the uh will know um on
let's say friday or or
thursday before the very
simple uh deliverable which is
only contact info right
and the reason we cannot
release the team member
list earlier is because
every semester we have
students dropping the courses
close to or even after
the group project.
And we want to minimize
the change in the
team members. So that
is the reason. And I
want to assure students
that on Saturday,
we have the first
deliverable, which we call it
deliverable zero to signify
that it is really simple. is
only is only the the contact
info and that's it. It
means that students will have
around seven days to know
about each other before
the first real assignment
approved projects opens so
it should not affect any
students and even for those
who are working full-time,
you guys should even
have a weekend in between
to get to know each
other before the due date
of the first real assignment
of group projects.
So that is the long
answer for that question.
Did you get to the second
half, which is when do
grid releases normally
happen? I didn't hear it
in there, but I wasn't
fully paying attention.
Something else was happening.
It was not in my answer.
On the other hand, it is
in the syllabus, which
say that normally we tend
to stay two weeks, but
sometimes it may need more.
And we have office
hours almost weekly.
So in every week, we
will just update students
how's the grading
going on, et cetera.
That being said,
any grading that can
be automated is
already automated.
So for any automated,
Barring any,
let's say, plagiarism
or violation,
what you see on
Gradescope is what
you will get on the
canvas of scoring.
Only certain parts.
Be careful of some assignments.
For instance,
there's an assignment
that comes up where you go
through Gradescope, and it
will give you a grade, but it
gives you a grade out of 10
points and basically it's
it's a it's a safety check
that makes sure you did
all the this the simple
things um if you get a zero
there you will get a zero
if you get the 10 points
there it doesn't necessarily
mean that you have full
points on the assignment
it just means that you have
gotten it to the point where
you know we can grade it.
That's a really
good clarification.
So first of all, every
Grayscope assignment
has 100 points. So if
you have zero over 100,
you for sure will have
zero points for that
assignment. If you have
10 points over 100,
it doesn't mean that
you have 10 points. It
depends on the later manual
grading, it can be 100
points. It can also be
five points in case all
of your answer is wrong
after manual grading.
So yeah, that's a really
good clarification.
Yep.
But yeah, back.
So for manual grading,
two weeks or a
little bit more for
automatic grading,
mostly what you see
is what you get.
All right. Next question
is once teams are
formed, Are we stuck
with Microsoft Teams for
communication, or can
we use any tool of
our choice to collaborate
with team members?
Students are quite ahead
this semester, I see.
Well, supposedly, we have
that instruction in group
project assignment. but
well it is no secret so
yeah um students can have an
agreement on using anything
it can be teams it can
be discord it can be ad
chat it can be uh what x
twitter telegram signal
yeah and anything all right
the next question is i
wanted to check whether the
current github repository
will be used for all future
assignments or if each
assignment will have
its own repo. I'm asking
because I'd like to know if
it's safe to reset the repo
now or if I should keep
it as is for continuity.
I can answer that
one if you want?
Yeah, please.
So you will use the same repo
for all of the individual
assignments. There will
be a separate one for
your team for the group
assignment, but for the
individual assignments, you
will use that same one. So
if you reset it at some
point, uh be careful of that
you know in the in the in
the first assignment there's
a instructions to reset
if you screw something
up uh or is that the second
i forget anyway um uh but
after the assignment that
tells you how to do it
in case you screw things
up don't do it again during
the semester because if
you reset it and your work
goes away uh because you're
working on assignment
five and you reset it and we
haven't finished assignment
four yet we suddenly
don't have anything to
grade. So at this point,
you can reset things back to
the beginning if you've
******* up that assignment
and need to start over
again, but don't do it later.
Anything to add?
No, you assigned it perfectly.
Okay, and the last one
at the moment is, should
I wait for the assignment
three to be released
and then try the JUnit
tutorial so I can set up
IntelliJ, et cetera,
relevant to assignment three?
um no opinion to be
honest you can you can
already get started now
and um and then have some
toy um toy problem and
then start with that first
if you want to otherwise
yeah you can also wait
will any different
opinion no i agree
i would get the
stuff uh installed um
if there's any changes or
setup that you need to do
after assignment three comes
out that's fine but you
you probably you know i
would get it installed and
get it ready um if you
have the time and you want
to do it uh and the next
new last question at least
for the moment is i understand
that the following will
be used in this court
course get java development
kit intellij idea ultimate
edition android studio
and the uml editor i
understand we'll be introduced
to these during the course
but any recommendations on
additional resources to
become familiar with these
um familiar with the the
tunes i i assume well
i mean you know the the
first assignment or the
second assignment again
i forget which is what
number it is now but uh
we'll get you um uh familiar
with Git. The Java
development kit, hopefully
you'll get familiar with
that as you go along.
Ultimately, you know,
IntelliJ, again, that's
part of developing in
Java. You should be good
with that. Android Studio
is essentially very
similar to IntelliJ.
It's just optimized for
coding for Android.
A UML editor is the one that
kind of is going to be up
to you. isn't that right or
do we have a specific one
now no we don't have any
well the instruction nor the
instructional staff does not
expect the student to use
any particular uml editor
we just expect the diagram
like the the either the image
the gpeg or pdf that's it
so yeah so that i mean that's
basically a drawing tool
and there are there are a
zillion of them out there
And I wouldn't go nuts trying
to find the most sophisticated
one because, you know,
you basically just need a
way to draw boxes and arrows
and the stuff you need for
a UML diagram. So but no,
we don't have a specific
one we recommend. You'll just
find it when you need it.
By the way, in case you're
wondering why I have a
tendency to start answering
questions, back when
this course was still
taught on the web equivalent
of stone tablets, I was
the head TA, and I handed
that over to Shin a
while ago, and he does a
much better job of it than
I did, but I still have
a tendency to jump in and
answer questions instead
of letting Shin do it.
And then I have to back to
him and say, wait, has
anything changed? So that's
where that died, you
know, that's coming from.
No, no worry. And,
and just, just to, for
the record, yeah,
it was a Rick for a
while. And then I took
over and actually,
Will, you, you left
for a while, did
you? And then you,
you came back, right?
Right.
I left for, for two or two
semesters or three semesters
or something, but they
don't know Rick. So I did, I
ignored Rick because they
don't know him. But yeah,
there was another guy in
between. I left for a couple
semesters because there were
some personal issues, and then
I came back as a regular
TA because Shin had it in
really good shape, and so I
didn't feel like there was
any point in wrestling him
for something he was doing
better than I did anyway.
We do have another question.
To follow up on my
previous question about
resetting the repo, what
do you suggest for future
assignments when we make
a mistake since we can't
reset anymore? Also,
would you prefer that we
use separate branches for
each assignment or keep
everything in main?
Thanks for your guidance.
In terms of resetting the
repo, normally in Git, you
don't reset a repo. It's not
something that you generally
do. The reason you have to
on that one assignment is
because to get you familiar
with Git, we have you run
a specific set of steps to
get used to what Git does.
And as a result, since
you need to follow them
exactly, if it's not right,
you need to start over.
But in a normal circumstances
using get, there
will be very few reasons
to have to reset.
I'm not going to say there
will never be any, but
it is very, very rare.
When you make a mistake
using, you know, when
you notice you've done
something wrong in an
assignment, you fix it and you
check in the fix and it
replaces the old thing.
because normally you're not
worried about the structure
of the git you're worried
about what the current
thing in git is so checking
in a change to fix your bug
uh overwrites the old stuff
and you're good um so yeah
the the reset is only because
that one assignment is
is is about the structure of
the repo and not about the
contents of the repo so
therefore reset is necessary
if you screw up the structure
i hope that makes sense
have anything dad okay
um right so let me
also check do we have
any other standing
question right now
that's all i'm seeing
okay so if that's the
case we can wait a little
bit more and if there
are no other questions we
can call it a night but
meanwhile I just want to
give some caution or warning
that and and we do this
every semester as we can
testify that But up until A4,
so A1, A2, A3, A4, they are
just warm up, and students,
most of students have a
full score, 100, over 100.
And then we have A5,
relatively easy as well,
and then group project.
And then A6 is the most,
A6 will be the most
intellectual challenging
and that is every
semester. The students will
have a shock when they
receive the assignment.
another shock when
we have the office
hour where we go
through the solution
and a third shock when
the way when they receive
the grade so i just want
to give advanced warning
for everyone and we
will also post the grade
statistics across the semester
so that this semester,
spring 2026, students
will be able to see grade
statistics from fall
2025 and see the changes.
And later on when we
release the grades for
assignment six of this
semester, we will also
post that and students
can also see whether this
semester is significantly
harder than the
previous one or just
about the same or easier.
So, again, do not extrapolate
your score up until
A5 to A6 because it will
be so much different.
I want to say something because
you're scaring students.
So, I think that the point
is that A6 is a little
different from the other
assignment because it's
about reasoning on the
theory that you have learned,
right? And software
development is not just about
doing, it's about
understanding the principle.
And so there is a lot
of thinking involved.
It's not a lot of work,
it's a lot of thinking.
And you just need to
approach this in a very lucid
way, considering that this
is a little different from
the other assignment that
you received up to that
point uh but it doesn't
necessarily mean so statistics
are made by data that we
collect so it's up to you
to change the statistic for
this semester you just need
to to approach this as
a way to reason and to
reflect on the problem you
receive knowing uh what you
have learned in the lecture
so now i wanted to add
something you are in very
good hands this is a great
team of TAs I joined this
team in the middle of last
semester but I'm familiar
with the class so when you
see the drawing that's
that's my drawing not my end
the one you see but the
drawing is mine so I know the
course from the beginning
and and you have all the
theory and all the information
in your lecture to do
well just put the effort to
try to really reason about
the question and not
don't be weak in answering
right it doesn't have to be
long you just need to reason
and and try to arrive to
the conclusion for that
the question you receive
that and you have all the
information you need to
answer correctly so don't get
scared it's it's more
difficult it's intellectually
more challenging but it's
totally at reach if you really
understand so maybe have
questions about the lecture
if you think you didn't
understand something but
you can do great
I didn't want you to scare our
students the first office hour
wait until the second
office hour then you can
terrify them there's another
question here that says
are there any book
recommendations for the course
jen you still
there yeah yeah um
so any books uh
recommendation um
in the past i think i
i mean not the book i
recommend for this course
but um i i do read myself
for software development
in general like the
uh the clean code series
from uncle bob um Test
-driven, not test-driven,
Domain-Driven Design.
I forgot the other.
And yeah, so those
are the books that I,
as an engineer working
in industry values.
But Will and Paula, any others?
Let me find Domain
-Driven Design.
i'm not uh i'm i'm
dyslexic probably something
you don't really need to
know so i'm not really a
good person to ask for
books because i it's not
the way i learn no i i
would have like a different
book for a different lecture
actually so i don't know
if it's such a good idea
so i would have like some
books for testing from some
books for requirements so
i i don't know um i wouldn't
know i i'll think more
about this there's another
question here um and i think
it's a good one it says from
my understanding in these
office hours we're not
allowed to ask questions
about the assignments um
that's so here's the problem
yeah you're you can ask
questions about the assignment
You can't ask anything
that's going to lead somebody
else to an answer they
should be finding themselves.
So if you have a question
about a definition, if you
don't understand what the
assignment is asking for,
that's the kind of stuff
you can ask. If you're
saying, hey, I wrote this as
my solution, is that good?
Definitely don't
ask that question
publicly because
that is sharing code
and that is an honor
code violation.
So you want to be careful,
but we're not saying you
can't ask any questions
about the assignments. You
just want to think in terms
of is your question about
the assignment or does
your question lead to the
answer in the assignment?
Because that's, you know, we
don't want you posting
anything that might lead
somebody to an answer or
worse to an incorrect answer.
And if you ask something,
the answer to which
would help, you know,
would be more than we want
to give you, you know,
that's something you should
be doing. we will say,
we can't answer that
because that's what you're
supposed to be doing.
But you're not prohibited
from asking questions
about the assignments.
Just be smart about it.
Jen, you want to add
anything? Yeah, they have
to be about the assignment
and not the solution.
Right.
And the second
question, we'll not be
able to speak in
these office hours.
We mentioned that earlier.
The problem is when we
started doing office hours,
there was some question as
to whether requiring people
to ask questions on screen
violated FERPA because
people might have to broadcast
and not want to. So the
decision was made to do
all the questions. You type
the questions in ed and
then we answer them here. um
it's it's just it became
too difficult to try and
figure out how to juggle
between the two of them and
and you know then have a
student complain wait i thought
i had to ask it there
and that's violates my
privacy whatever it's just
easier to do it this way um
it it's not necessarily
easier but it's easier from a
logistical standpoint so
that's the way we do it uh
the next question is do
we need to worry about the
content in P1 Lecture 3,
which is not included in Ed
this semester? I never used
IntelliJ IDEA, so I worry
that it may become a problem
in future assignments.
Chen?
Yeah.
Sorry, I have something else.
So let me see. So the question.
Do we need to worry about
the contents in P1 Lecture 3?
Well, actually,
that one is replaced
by the JUnit
tutorial externally.
So, no, you should not be
worried about that at all.
All righty. And that is, once
again, the current last one.
Okay.
So, Paola,
any final message
for the students
before we're
concluding for the day?
I'm very happy you didn't
use the word wise again,
because I was saying you're
asking for a lot of wisdom.
No,
I just want to say
again, welcome.
And it's very nice to
see so many of you join
live and all these many
questions. just stay
engaged work well with
your group and you know
you have an amazing team
of TAs here and I mean you
see much more of them than
me but I'm in the loop for
everything that happened so
you are in very good hand
and I hope this is going
to be a great semester and
I'm pretty sure you're
going to learn a ton so
it's great to be here from
the beginning this semester
all righty um there was
one more question i just
answered in in in it's about
uml editors again but there's
no point in discussing
that at this point because
that's several weeks away
so we'll discuss it when it
gets closer ask the question
again if you still are
curious when that assignment
opens up okay right then
if that's the case then
thank you everyone and uh
yeah Yeah, I will let Will
and Palau also say goodbye.
Good luck, everyone.
Have a great
semester. I hope it
all goes well for you.
Yeah, good luck. And I hope
everything goes great for
your semester, not just in
this class, but any other
class you're taking. It's
great to have you here.
All right. So long.
Bye, all.